<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Summer Health Engineering Blog</title>
        <link>https://summer-health.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Summer Health Engineering Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Summer Health Engineering]]></title>
            <link>https://summer-health.github.io/blog/summer-health-engineering</link>
            <guid>https://summer-health.github.io/blog/summer-health-engineering</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[About our engineering team]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Summer Health Engineering Banner" src="/assets/images/summer-health-banner-0ee08b221f4e232743b636c009d139f3.png" width="1280" height="515" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>At Summer Health, we're reinventing the world of pediatric care with a unique
vision: to place a doctor in every parent's pocket. With an innovative platform
that connects parents to a pediatrician within 15 minutes, our commitment to
healthcare is as uncomplicated as sending a text message. This formidable
challenge of integrating healthcare, technology, and convenience presents our
team with a wealth of engineering problems. However, our growth-minded,
problem-solving approach helps us continually rise to these challenges.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-growth-mindset">Our Growth Mindset<a href="#our-growth-mindset" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Growth Mindset" title="Direct link to Our Growth Mindset">​</a></h2><p>Central to our engineering team's philosophy is a strong growth mindset.
Everything we do is focused on continual improvement - whether it's our
processes, our technology stack, conventions, or even our team dynamics.
Every team member is encouraged to contribute to this process of evolution.
From refining code, streamlining workflows or reducing meeting redundancies,
every bit helps to ensure we operate at peak efficiency.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="problem-solvers-not-just-delivery-engineers">Problem Solvers, Not Just Delivery Engineers<a href="#problem-solvers-not-just-delivery-engineers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Problem Solvers, Not Just Delivery Engineers" title="Direct link to Problem Solvers, Not Just Delivery Engineers">​</a></h2><p>Another key aspect that sets us apart is that we are not just "delivery engineers"
– we're a problem-solving team. Our engineers play an integral role in the
creative process, defining, understanding, and formulating solutions for the
challenges we face. This mindset takes us beyond simply delivering a product;
it turns us into innovators, continually reshaping our approach to ensure we
provide the best pediatric care.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="diversity-and-inclusion">Diversity and Inclusion<a href="#diversity-and-inclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Diversity and Inclusion" title="Direct link to Diversity and Inclusion">​</a></h2><p>We believe in the power of diversity and inclusivity. We strive to create an
environment where all team members can show up as their authentic selves,
contribute their unique perspectives, and feel valued. Our team members'
diverse backgrounds and thoughts are not just appreciated - they're essential
to our success. The richness of ideas, viewpoints, and experiences that stem
from this diversity fosters innovation, drives creativity, and enables us to
solve complex problems in novel ways.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="high-collaboration-high-iteration">High Collaboration, High Iteration<a href="#high-collaboration-high-iteration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to High Collaboration, High Iteration" title="Direct link to High Collaboration, High Iteration">​</a></h2><p>Our day-to-day is highly collaborative and iterative. We implement practices
like continuous integration, continuous delivery, and continuous deployment,
encouraging engineers to merge multiple items to production daily. By breaking
down features into smaller increments, we can rally around similar goals,
accelerating our critical path quickly.</p><p>Pair programming is a cornerstone of our team culture, and we also place
immense value on internal documentation to help each other understand ideas
and align on conventions. We're always seeking ways to improve our productivity,
and often, this means turning convention into automation so we can focus on
the problems that matter most.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="into-the-future">Into the Future<a href="#into-the-future" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Into the Future" title="Direct link to Into the Future">​</a></h2><p>At Summer Health, we're leveraging technology and teamwork to transform pediatric
care, bringing it to parents' fingertips. Our growth-minded, problem-solving
engineering team is at the heart of this revolution, driving us forward, one
line of code at a time. We're not just writing software; we're writing the
future of pediatric care!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>team</category>
            <category>engineering</category>
            <category>ai-assisted</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>