<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Summer Health Engineering Blog</title>
        <link>https://summer-health.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Summer Health Engineering Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Better Provider Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://summer-health.github.io/blog/2023/08/10/care-os</link>
            <guid>https://summer-health.github.io/blog/2023/08/10/care-os</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[How we're building a world-class experience for pediatricians]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every pediatrician knows the strain of a cluttered and convoluted Electronic
Health Record (EHR) system. The age-old EHR systems, teeming with irrelevant
fields and buttons, can bring back painful memories. What exacerbates this is
that these traditional EHRs are focused on appointments and billing
instead of being focused on providing care.</p><p>Summer Health focuses on direct-to-consumer care that's available around the
clock. We're not just streamlining healthcare for parents; we're tailoring it
for the pediatricians so they can provide the highest quality care without
being burdened by outdated tech.</p><p>We envision a healthcare experience that enables quality care without
sacrificing simplicity and security. From this vision, CareOS was born. However,
creating a new healthcare experience from the ground up takes a lot of work,
and we're not interested in reinventing the wheel. This post covers some core
concepts that were and continue to be important to us as we build a world-class
healthcare experience.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-right-foundation">The Right Foundation<a href="#the-right-foundation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Right Foundation" title="Direct link to The Right Foundation">​</a></h2><p>The fastest way to a skeptical look is by telling someone you're going
to build an EHR from scratch. It's a daunting task, and skepticism is warranted.
That's why while we knew we needed a better experience for our pediatricians,
building everything from scratch wasn't the right approach. We explored different
headless and headed options, weighing the limitations and expenses. We needed the
flexibility to build a custom experience without committing to a future operational
nightmare.</p><p>That's where Medplum came into play. Developer-friendly and forward-thinking,
Medplum's healthcare platform resonated with our vision and allowed us
to build a high quality experience without starting from 0.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="identity-management">Identity Management<a href="#identity-management" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Identity Management" title="Direct link to Identity Management">​</a></h2><p>Being a seed-stage company, Summer Health must keep the identities involved in
healthcare flexible. As we evolve and uncover new product dimensions, there's a
pressing need for adaptability. Yet, security remains paramount and clinical
data access needs to be restricted only to pertinent entities.</p><p>Recognizing this, we aimed for a healthcare platform that offers flexible
<a href="https://www.medplum.com/docs/auth" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">identity management</a>. So
whether it’s a Summer Health employee, a partnering practitioner or a parent,
we can operate in one environment under one auth umbrella.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="access-control">Access Control<a href="#access-control" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Access Control" title="Direct link to Access Control">​</a></h2><p>Figuring out identity management was just the tip of the iceberg. Pediatrics has
a unique challenge in terms of data access. Unlike other specialties, a
pediatric patient's clinical data must be accessible by different identities,
like parents or guardians. So, how do we ensure that the right individuals have
the correct access while ensuring the confidentiality and integrity of the data?
This complexity needs a
<a href="https://www.medplum.com/docs/auth/access-control" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">nuanced approach to access control</a>,
and we needed a platform with an answer.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="everything-is-on-fhir-">Everything is on FHIR 🔥<a href="#everything-is-on-fhir-" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Everything is on FHIR 🔥" title="Direct link to Everything is on FHIR 🔥">​</a></h2><p>Our vision was broader than the present. We knew our data storage methods
today would impact future interoperability with partners and other healthcare
systems. This led us to FHIR (Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources), a
standard framework for clinical data storage. Adopting FHIR meant ensuring our
data remains legible outside the confines of Summer Health, promising a brighter
future for our patients and their relationships with other clinical entities.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="mobile-first">Mobile First<a href="#mobile-first" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Mobile First" title="Direct link to Mobile First">​</a></h2><p>Our pediatricians, much like our parents, rely on mobile devices. The availability
of Summer Health across the US, every single day of the week, 24 hours a day, is
rooted in mobile accessibility. It's pivotal for our pediatricians to
provide uninterrupted, high-quality care, irrespective of their location.
We wanted to craft a user-friendly, mobile-first experience for them, ensuring
they have all the necessary information at their fingertips to provide
the highest quality care.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="CareOS screenshots" src="/assets/images/care-os-screenshots-f6d236fa407b0eea40e9f49bd4443d7e.png" width="3240" height="2400" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="more-to-come">More to Come<a href="#more-to-come" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to More to Come" title="Direct link to More to Come">​</a></h2><p>Summer Health’s path to revolutionize pediatric care starts with ensuring our
pediatricians have the best tools to provide the best care. We’ll continue to
share more about how we’re building CareOS as we continue this journey. In the
meantime, you can learn more details about our integration with Medplum in the
case study:
<a href="https://www.medplum.com/blog/summer-case-study" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">24/7 Pediatrician Access - Summer Health Case Study</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>engineering</category>
            <category>fhir</category>
            <category>ai-assisted</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Summer Health Engineering]]></title>
            <link>https://summer-health.github.io/blog/summer-health-engineering</link>
            <guid>https://summer-health.github.io/blog/summer-health-engineering</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[About our engineering team]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Summer Health Engineering Banner" src="/assets/images/summer-health-banner-0ee08b221f4e232743b636c009d139f3.png" width="1280" height="515" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>At Summer Health, we're reinventing the world of pediatric care with a unique
vision: to place a doctor in every parent's pocket. With an innovative platform
that connects parents to a pediatrician within 15 minutes, our commitment to
healthcare is as uncomplicated as sending a text message. This formidable
challenge of integrating healthcare, technology, and convenience presents our
team with a wealth of engineering problems. However, our growth-minded,
problem-solving approach helps us continually rise to these challenges.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-growth-mindset">Our Growth Mindset<a href="#our-growth-mindset" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Growth Mindset" title="Direct link to Our Growth Mindset">​</a></h2><p>Central to our engineering team's philosophy is a strong growth mindset.
Everything we do is focused on continual improvement - whether it's our
processes, our technology stack, conventions, or even our team dynamics.
Every team member is encouraged to contribute to this process of evolution.
From refining code, streamlining workflows or reducing meeting redundancies,
every bit helps to ensure we operate at peak efficiency.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="problem-solvers-not-just-delivery-engineers">Problem Solvers, Not Just Delivery Engineers<a href="#problem-solvers-not-just-delivery-engineers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Problem Solvers, Not Just Delivery Engineers" title="Direct link to Problem Solvers, Not Just Delivery Engineers">​</a></h2><p>Another key aspect that sets us apart is that we are not just "delivery engineers"
– we're a problem-solving team. Our engineers play an integral role in the
creative process, defining, understanding, and formulating solutions for the
challenges we face. This mindset takes us beyond simply delivering a product;
it turns us into innovators, continually reshaping our approach to ensure we
provide the best pediatric care.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="diversity-and-inclusion">Diversity and Inclusion<a href="#diversity-and-inclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Diversity and Inclusion" title="Direct link to Diversity and Inclusion">​</a></h2><p>We believe in the power of diversity and inclusivity. We strive to create an
environment where all team members can show up as their authentic selves,
contribute their unique perspectives, and feel valued. Our team members'
diverse backgrounds and thoughts are not just appreciated - they're essential
to our success. The richness of ideas, viewpoints, and experiences that stem
from this diversity fosters innovation, drives creativity, and enables us to
solve complex problems in novel ways.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="high-collaboration-high-iteration">High Collaboration, High Iteration<a href="#high-collaboration-high-iteration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to High Collaboration, High Iteration" title="Direct link to High Collaboration, High Iteration">​</a></h2><p>Our day-to-day is highly collaborative and iterative. We implement practices
like continuous integration, continuous delivery, and continuous deployment,
encouraging engineers to merge multiple items to production daily. By breaking
down features into smaller increments, we can rally around similar goals,
accelerating our critical path quickly.</p><p>Pair programming is a cornerstone of our team culture, and we also place
immense value on internal documentation to help each other understand ideas
and align on conventions. We're always seeking ways to improve our productivity,
and often, this means turning convention into automation so we can focus on
the problems that matter most.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="into-the-future">Into the Future<a href="#into-the-future" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Into the Future" title="Direct link to Into the Future">​</a></h2><p>At Summer Health, we're leveraging technology and teamwork to transform pediatric
care, bringing it to parents' fingertips. Our growth-minded, problem-solving
engineering team is at the heart of this revolution, driving us forward, one
line of code at a time. We're not just writing software; we're writing the
future of pediatric care!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>team</category>
            <category>engineering</category>
            <category>ai-assisted</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>